<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lab 5 on taskcat workshop</title>
    <link>/500_lab5.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lab 5 on taskcat workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="/500_lab5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Initialize Git repo</title>
      <link>/500_lab5/1_page.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/500_lab5/1_page.html</guid>
      <description>To create a CICD pipeline for your project, you need a git repository. This repository will contain all the source code of your project and will be the source to trigger your pipeline.
For this lab, you will use AWS CodeCommit for your project&amp;rsquo;s git repository. We have already pre-created a Code Commit repsoitory in your team&amp;rsquo;s AWS Account. Click the following link to open the AWS CodeCommit console in a new tab of your browser.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy CI/CD pipeline</title>
      <link>/500_lab5/10_page.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/500_lab5/10_page.html</guid>
      <description>Now, it&amp;rsquo;s time to setup a CICD pipeline for your project. To do that, go to your team&amp;rsquo;s dasbhoard and make a note of the following values. You will need this to create the pipeline.
 Your AWS Code Commit repository Url (https://) Your AWS Code Commit repository name - quiz-app  Launch stack To create a CICD pipeline, you will use a CloudFormation template. Click the following button to launch a stack creation for the CICD pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>View test and code promotion</title>
      <link>/500_lab5/20_page.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/500_lab5/20_page.html</guid>
      <description>Now, after your stack creation is completed successfully and you have a CICD pipeline setup, let&amp;rsquo;s see what does the pipeline do.
View CICD pipeline On your Cloudformation console, click the Outputs tab.
Look for CodePipelineURL, and open the link in a new tab in your browser.
This will open the AWS Code Pipeline console, and you should see a pipeline.
You may see that, either the Source action or the Build action is in-progress.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
